<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IM-LAB on IM-LAB</title>
    <link>http://hakyimlab.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IM-LAB on IM-LAB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Hae Kyung Im</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bidding Farewell to Scott</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/scott-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 13:52:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/scott-farewell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After two years in the Lab, Scott has decided to join the well paid workforce. Scott is a wonderful colleague to all of us and has made important contributions to our team. Thank you and best of lucks, Scott 🍀🍀🍀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/scott-farewell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also thank you, Wenndy, for organizing and buying the present for Scott.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene Correlation Across Tissues</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/project/gene-correlation-across-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 18:36:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/project/gene-correlation-across-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This app plots the correlation of predicted expression levels in different tissues. The prediction was computed using GTEx v6p prediction models  and 1000G genotypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[code link will be posted here shortly]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imlab.shinyapps.io/GeneExpressionCorr_v6p_HapMap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;User friendly web application here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations of PrediXcan association results</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/limitations-predixcan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 15:24:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/limitations-predixcan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that significant associations shown here do not imply causality. That said, given that PrediXcan is seeking to test the role of gene expression variation on traits and we and others have shown that significant PrediXcan genes are enriched in causal genes, these results should be useful to delve into the mechanisms underlying gene to phenotype associations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;False positives can arise because of several factors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD contamination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By computing the probability of LD contamination, we try to reduce false positives due to LD rather than genuine colocalization of trait and expression causal variants. Filtering out genes with high probability of independent signals (P3&amp;gt;0.5) would reduce the number of hits due to LD contamination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co regulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many loci show regulation of multiple genes. PrediXcan is not able to distinguish between truly causal and co-regulation but non causal genes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mismatched LD between study, reference, and training sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misspecified LD can lead to false positives (for example if LD in the study population is much higher than in the reference population, highly correlated modestly significant SNPs may be considered to be independent evidence of association, leading to highly significant gene-level association). They are also needed for combining results across multiple tissues, or to run conditional analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerabilities of the &#39;Vulnerabilities of transcriptome wide association studies&#39; argument</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 13:24:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PrediXcan and other transcriptome wide association study (TWAS) methods discover and prioritize genes based on a functional mechanism &amp;ndash;regulation of gene expression. We agree that we have to temper over-enthusiasm, but Wainberg et al&amp;rsquo;s paper could represent a backlash to the enthusiasm that the community has for this approach, which we believe is well placed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are our responses to some of the statements of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PrediXcan/TWAS associations do not imply causality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we have explicitly stated that we do not claim causality but agree that the message needs to be emphasized. However, the over-interpretation of TWAS results as causal (which itself seems overstated by Wainberg et al), is precisely because of the exciting aspect of TWAS as association testing ‘through a lens’ of a particular functional mechanism that we believe is very important, namely, regulation of gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TWAS is vulnerable to find multiple associated genes because of co-regulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, when a GWAS lead SNP is associated with the expression of several local co-regulated genes, TWAS will yield multiple associated genes. No one would argue that a TWAS result implicating multiple local genes should be interpreted as meaning that all of those genes are likely to be contributing to the trait. But assuming that a single gene is always at the root of a GWAS or TWAS signal also seems unnecessarily restrictive. Molecular biology and model organism genetics would suggest that allelic heterogeneity should be the norm. Although admittedly we don’t see huge evidence for it in complex trait GWAS, we do see it in eQTL data and arguably this is a reason why TWAS discovers new genes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A different source of false positive associations (not considered by Wainberg et al) is LD contamination. This phenomenon occurs, for example, when a variant alters expression of a gene but a different variant is causing changes in the phenotype but both variants are in LD. Unlike the coregulation confounding, which can only be teased out via wet lab experiments, LD contamination may be quantified and corrected. As for GWAS loci, fine mapping and conditional analysis may be used to addressed this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“TWAS exhibits instability when tissue/expression panel is changed”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expectation that an association found in one tissue should also be found in another one seems to be the problem. A better way to describe these results is that when a gene exhibits tissue-specific genetic regulation, we cannot be surprised to see tissue-specific phenotype associations. This is, we would argue, a feature not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the regulatory mechanism is highly context specific, it is possible and likely that none of the reference transcriptome dataset has captured it. This is not a limitation of the approach, but rather of the data available for investigation. We cannot build predictive models without training data, and genes expressed in a single cell type that is poorly represented in available tissues will not be well interrogated with the method, which has been widely acknowledged in the original publications as a limitation of the method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“False positive rate is high but unquantifiable”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would Wainberg et al. consider traditional GWAS to have a high false positive rate due to the large number of associations attributable to LD?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TWAS is simply a weighted burden test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We agree that it is a weighted burden test analytically, but of course the weights have meaning, and that is the effect of the variants on gene expression. Therefore, this weighted burden test is exactly what it purports to be: an association test of a trait with genetically regulated expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is the results of discussions among (in alphabetic order)
Nancy Cox,
Eric Gamazon,
Laura Huckins,
Hae Kyung Im,
Douglas  Ruderfer,
Pamela Sklar, and
Eli Stahl.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome prediction models are robust across populations</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/robustnes-across-populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 17:19:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/robustnes-across-populations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most GWAS and eQTL studies have been performed in European samples. So how well do models trained in Europeans translate to other populations? Segal et al have shown that predictions of gene expression levels are robust across populations (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1003396&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following figure shows the p-value of the correlation between predicted and observed expression levels in European and African samples from the 1000 Genomes set (GEUVADIS RNA-seq) using model trained in GTEx with majority European individuals. As expected performance decreases (blue is more significant than red) when we apply to African samples but the correlation is still quite significant.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/geuvadis-performance-EUR-AFR.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

So et al use S-PrediXcan to find psychiatric drug repositioning candidates.

## to add figure
![](https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/so2017.png)
---&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Alvaro</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/alvaros-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 14:51:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/alvaros-baby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the birth of Alvaro&amp;rsquo;s baby girl 👶. Congratulations, Alvaro!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the phenome-wide consequences of genetically regulated molecular traits</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-19-ashg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-19-ashg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Apps</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/project/web-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:08:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/project/web-apps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are releasing all PrediXcan associations based on Neale Lab&#39;s UKB rapid GWAS results</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/ubk-neale-predixcan-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/ubk-neale-predixcan-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Update (11/1/2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gene level results &amp;ldquo;meta analyzed&amp;rdquo; across tissues now available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shinyapp to directly query by gene and phenotype is &lt;a href=&#34;http://UKBBeta.gene2pheno.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; but can be slow. Stay tuned for faster version coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many of you may know, Neale Lab made a big splash in the GWAS community by releasing the summary results of 2400+ phenotypes from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nealelab.is/blog/2017/7/19/rapid-gwas-of-thousands-of-phenotypes-for-337000-samples-in-the-uk-biobank&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UK Biobank&lt;/a&gt;.
Following their lead on open science and open data sharing, we are releasing the bulk runs of PrediXcan association based on Neale Lab&amp;rsquo;s UKB results and 44 tissues models from GTEx V6p release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All PrediXcan associations can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ukb-neale.gene2pheno.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also generating a &amp;ldquo;meta analyzed&amp;rdquo; across tissues version, which we find much more easily interpretable. They will be uploaded within the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this is work in progress, so feedback is greatly appreciated! We are trying to flag some suspicous results (likely false positives) but so please let us know if you find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Web app for query (Shinyapp) will be rolled out shortly, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical methods to explore the phenotypic consequences of gene regulation</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-13-wcpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 18:51:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-13-wcpg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Friday, October 13, 2017 from 8:00am - 3:45pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImLab was awarded NIH Cloud Credit</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/nih-cloud-credit-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 10:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/nih-cloud-credit-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to be awarded NIH Cloud Credit that will help us fund our cloud-based web applications and databases and broadly share our tools and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Jiamao, for pushing this through 👍😃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information about Cloud Credits &lt;a href=&#34;https://commonfund.nih.gov/bd2k/cloudcredits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U4C Challenge Winners</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/u4c-challenge-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 10:19:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/u4c-challenge-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two out of 4 winners used PrediXcan 👍👍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners of &amp;ldquo;Up For A Challenge (U4C): Stimulating innovation in breast cancer genetic epidemiology&amp;rdquo; papers published on line &lt;a href=&#34;http://collections.plos.org/up-for-a-challenge&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is our contribution in collaboration with Guimin Gao, Brandon Pierce, Funmi Olopade, and Dezheng Huo &lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006727&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link to paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the phenotypic consequences of every human gene...</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-13-rising-starts-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 08:28:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-13-rising-starts-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medicine.uchicago.edu/files/2017/08/Rising_Stars_Poster_FINAL.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Event Poster PDF here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating GWAS, omics, and electronic medical records to dissect disease biology</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-08-gcd-iges-joint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 20:05:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-08-gcd-iges-joint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S-PrediXcan (MetaXcan) in drug repositioning</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/drug-repositioning-metaxcan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/drug-repositioning-metaxcan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So et al use S-PrediXcan to find psychiatric drug repositioning candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/so2017.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
