<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IM-LAB on IM-LAB</title>
    <link>http://hakyimlab.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IM-LAB on IM-LAB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Hae Kyung Im</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>GTEx V7 Prediction Model Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/v7-v6p-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/v7-v6p-analysis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are releasing prediction models trained on GTEx Version 7 data. Download from &lt;a href=&#34;http://predictdb.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We have updated our processing pipeline, and restricted to individuals of European ancestry to obtain more reliable LD data. This reduces false positives in the Summary Version of PrediXcan. Because of this choice, the gain in sample size relative to V6p is modest (ranging from -18 to 89), with whole blood, LCLs and fibroblasts experiencing reduced sample size. We developed a new criteria to assess model performance. We have also decided to include prediction models for both pseudogenes and lincRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While preparing GTEx V7 prediction models, we identified a few issues in the way prediction performance was estimated in the previous release (2016-09-08 release). In aggregate, these caused the prediction model performance to be overestimated. Reassuringly, predicted expression levels and the downstream associations with phenotypes remain mostly unchanged, even though prediction weights vary slightly. However, some gene/tissue pairs are no longer considered reliable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detailed description of the pipeline update and the effect in prediction models performance and downstream S-PrediXcan association can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/v7-v6p-analysis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;comparison-between-v7-and-v6p-new-and-old-pipeline&#34;&gt;Comparison between V7 and V6p, new and old pipeline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we compare prediction models based on GTEx V6p (2016-09-08) and V7. While training the V7 models we identified a few issues in the V6 pipeline used for the September and November 2016 release. We identified 3 issues in the V6p pipeline used in the release of September 2016. We describe here the issues, the consequences in prediction performance estimates and downstream S-PrediXcan association, and the fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;issue-1-penalization-parameter-was-estimated-in-sample-using-all-the-samples&#34;&gt;Issue 1: Penalization parameter was estimated in-sample (using all the samples)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V6p old pipeline computed R2 using lambda estimated from all data. This led to overestimates of the performance measures. See Figure 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We classified gene/tissue pairs with negative correlation in the red group (to be dropped). This proportion ranges from 6 to 13%, with larger proportions for tissues with smaller sample sizes. If a more conservative cutoff of 0.10 is used, 22% to 29% of genes would be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;issue-2-there-was-induced-negative-correlation-between-training-and-test-sets&#34;&gt;Issue 2: There was induced negative correlation between training and test sets&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was causing a slight underestimation of performance. In the old pipeline, the correlation between predicted and actual was computed using all folds combined. The sample mean of the training set (which excludes the test fold) is necessarily of opposite sign to the sample mean of the fold (all data mean was 0, so that the test fold average is of opposite sign to the training set’s average). This effect leads to a small underestimation of the correlation. Figure 2 shows the correlation estimated within each fold and averaged across folds, which is slightly larger than the correlation from the old pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;issue-3-sign-of-correlation-predicted-vs-actual-was-ignored&#34;&gt;Issue 3: Sign of correlation (predicted vs actual) was ignored&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few genes that had negative correlation between predicted and actual but the old pipeline was accepting them as reliable model because it was only considering the square and the p-value of the correlation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;consequence-in-prediction-performance-measures&#34;&gt;Consequence in prediction performance measures&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combined consequence of the three bugs can be seen in Figure 1 where the correlation between predicted and actual (with in sample lambda for the old pipeline and out of sample lambda for the new pipeline) is shown. This error did not affect well predicted genes (upper right region of the plot). The lower left region shows that the old pipeline was over estimating the correlation (most points to the left of the identity line).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/GTEx-v7-release-notes/Fig1-V6p_old-vs-V6p_new-Adipose_Subcutaneous.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fig 1: Estimated correlation between predicted and observed expression levels. The old pipeline overestimated (y axis) the correlation between predicted and actual expression levels (x axis). The effect is more notable for at the lower end of correlations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows the old pipeline estimates on the y axis, and on the x-axis is the correlation using the in-sample (all data) lambda parameter but computing the correlation within each fold and averaging across folds. Therefore, Figure 2 is showing the effects of bugs 2 and 3. There are more points to the left of the identity line, indicating that bug 2 was underestimating the performance.
￼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/GTEx-v7-release-notes/Fig2-insample-V6p_old-vs-V6p_new-Adipose_Subcutaneous.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fig 2:  (in-sample lambda) cross validated correlation between predicted and actual expression level. The corrected pipeline’s correlation estimates tend to be larger (more points below the identity line) than the old pipeline’s estimates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;definition-of-color-coding-by-reliability&#34;&gt;Definition of color coding by reliability&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red:&lt;/strong&gt; gene/tissue pairs for which the correlation between predicted and actual expression (nested cross validation) levels were negative with the new pipeline with nested cross validation (all parameters including the penalization parameter lambda is computed without using the data to be predicted).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green:&lt;/strong&gt; gene/tissue pairs that pass the new more stringent performance criterion (nested cross validated correlation &amp;gt; 0.10, pvalue&lt;0.05, correlation of old and new pipeline prediction &gt; 0.9)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow:&lt;/strong&gt; remaining gene/tissue pairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;consequences-in-s-predixcan-results&#34;&gt;Consequences in S-PrediXcan results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, S-PrediXcan Z-scores remain mostly around the identity line. Figure 3 shows V7 vs V6 PrediXcan Z-scores for the height phenotype from the GIANT consortium. We also examined similar figures for over 40 phenotypes and found that
- Genes in common yield similar predixcan Z-scores
- Genes in V7 and not in V6p tend to be slightly more significant than genes in V6p and not in V7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/GTEx-v7-release-notes/Fig3-S-PrediXcan-Height-V7-vs-V6p.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;600&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Comparison of S-PrediXcan Z-score using V7 (y-axis) vs V6p (old pipeline). Most gene tissue pairs cluster around the identity line. Points strictly in horizontal axis and vertical axis correspond to gene/tissue pairs that were missing in the other version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;another-change-in-the-criterion-for-filtering-out-genes&#34;&gt;Another change in the criterion for filtering out genes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we were using FDR$&amp;lt;$0.05 to filter out genes (using genes within one tissue at a time). Genes for which no convergence was achieved were being ignored, causing another source of bias. One workaround was to assign a uniformly distributed p-values to non converging genes. After some thought, we preferred not to introduce another source of variability and decided on using the following criteria to filter out genes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nested cross validated correlation between predicted and actual levels &amp;gt; 0.10 (or equivalently R2&amp;gt;1%) and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p-value of the correlation test &amp;lt; 0.05.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prediction performance p-value and R2 will be provided for users who want to use a more stringent criterion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;should-you-switch-to-version-7&#34;&gt;Should you switch to version 7?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose to fit GTEx version 7 data using only Europeans. This has the benefit of allowing us to better estimate LD and making S-PrediXcan more robust, thus avoiding some uncommon but extreme false positive associations. When the correlation between SNPs is not properly estimated, S-PrediXcan may consider that for example two modest associations to be independent evidence of association and thus yield a very significant value when in fact in the study population the SNPs are highly correlated and the two signals should be considered to be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If S-PrediXcan will be used, then V7 is provide more robust associations and fewer instances of extreme false positive p-values. However, if individual level data are available, no extern al LD information is needed since the regression with individual level data will implicitly use the study population’s LD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 4 shows that in general, V7 has better performance measures (larger nested cross validated correlation between predicted and actual). This is probably due to the small increase in sample size (30, about 10% for adipose subcutaneous tissue as shown) and the homogeneity of the population (only Europeans were used in V7 training). However, there is a sizable number of genes with low performance in V7 but relatively good performance in V6p. It is possible that this improved performance in V6p is due to  the more diverse population representation in the V6p samples but further comparisons are needed to test this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/GTEx-v7-release-notes/Fig4-V6p_new-vs-V7-Adipose_Subcutaneous.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 4: Comparison of performance between V6p and V7 both with corrected pipeline. Nested cross validated correlation between predicted and actual expression levels in V6p vs V7 (adipose subcutaneous shown). Genes in V7 tend to have better performance, i.e. more points are located below the identity line. However, there is also a sizable number of genes that were relatively well predicted in V6p but have correlation near 0 in V7.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;workaround-for-manuscripts-analysis-in-advanced-stage&#34;&gt;Workaround for manuscripts/analysis in advanced stage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you in advanced stages of analysis/manuscript preparation, we have put together a table with three levels of reliability for each gene/tissue pair and recommend to use the following guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your top gene/tissue pairs are in the green list, no action is needed. If they fall in the red list, they should be dropped. Given the sharing across tissues of regulation, it is possible that even after dropping a gene/tissue pair, the gene is still significant and reliable in other tissues. Gene/tissue pairs in the yellow list should be considered with caution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bidding Farewell to Scott</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/scott-farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 13:52:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/scott-farewell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After two years in the Lab, Scott has decided to join the well paid workforce. Scott is a wonderful colleague to all of us and has made important contributions to our team. Thank you and best of lucks, Scott 🍀🍀🍀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/scott-farewell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also thank you, Wenndy, for organizing and buying the present for Scott.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene Correlation Across Tissues</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/project/gene-correlation-across-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 18:36:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/project/gene-correlation-across-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This app plots the correlation of predicted expression levels in different tissues. The prediction was computed using GTEx v6p prediction models  and 1000G genotypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[code link will be posted here shortly]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imlab.shinyapps.io/GeneExpressionCorr_v6p_HapMap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;User friendly web application here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations of PrediXcan association results</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/limitations-predixcan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 15:24:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/limitations-predixcan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that significant associations shown here do not imply causality. That said, given that PrediXcan is seeking to test the role of gene expression variation on traits and we and others have shown that significant PrediXcan genes are enriched in causal genes, these results should be useful to delve into the mechanisms underlying gene to phenotype associations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;False positives can arise because of several factors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LD contamination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By computing the probability of LD contamination, we try to reduce false positives due to LD rather than genuine colocalization of trait and expression causal variants. Filtering out genes with high probability of independent signals (P3&amp;gt;0.5) would reduce the number of hits due to LD contamination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co regulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many loci show regulation of multiple genes. PrediXcan is not able to distinguish between truly causal and co-regulation but non causal genes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mismatched LD between study, reference, and training sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misspecified LD can lead to false positives (for example if LD in the study population is much higher than in the reference population, highly correlated modestly significant SNPs may be considered to be independent evidence of association, leading to highly significant gene-level association). They are also needed for combining results across multiple tissues, or to run conditional analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerabilities of the &#39;Vulnerabilities of transcriptome wide association studies&#39; argument</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 13:24:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PrediXcan and other transcriptome wide association study (TWAS) methods discover and prioritize genes based on a functional mechanism &amp;ndash;regulation of gene expression. We agree that we have to temper over-enthusiasm, but Wainberg et al&amp;rsquo;s paper could represent a backlash to the enthusiasm that the community has for this approach, which we believe is well placed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are our responses to some of the statements of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PrediXcan/TWAS associations do not imply causality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we have explicitly stated that we do not claim causality but agree that the message needs to be emphasized. However, the over-interpretation of TWAS results as causal (which itself seems overstated by Wainberg et al), is precisely because of the exciting aspect of TWAS as association testing ‘through a lens’ of a particular functional mechanism that we believe is very important, namely, regulation of gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TWAS is vulnerable to find multiple associated genes because of co-regulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, when a GWAS lead SNP is associated with the expression of several local co-regulated genes, TWAS will yield multiple associated genes. No one would argue that a TWAS result implicating multiple local genes should be interpreted as meaning that all of those genes are likely to be contributing to the trait. But assuming that a single gene is always at the root of a GWAS or TWAS signal also seems unnecessarily restrictive. Molecular biology and model organism genetics would suggest that allelic heterogeneity should be the norm. Although admittedly we don’t see huge evidence for it in complex trait GWAS, we do see it in eQTL data and arguably this is a reason why TWAS discovers new genes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A different source of false positive associations (not considered by Wainberg et al) is LD contamination. This phenomenon occurs, for example, when a variant alters expression of a gene but a different variant is causing changes in the phenotype but both variants are in LD. Unlike the coregulation confounding, which can only be teased out via wet lab experiments, LD contamination may be quantified and corrected. As for GWAS loci, fine mapping and conditional analysis may be used to addressed this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“TWAS exhibits instability when tissue/expression panel is changed”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The expectation that an association found in one tissue should also be found in another one seems to be the problem. A better way to describe these results is that when a gene exhibits tissue-specific genetic regulation, we cannot be surprised to see tissue-specific phenotype associations. This is, we would argue, a feature not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the regulatory mechanism is highly context specific, it is possible and likely that none of the reference transcriptome dataset has captured it. This is not a limitation of the approach, but rather of the data available for investigation. We cannot build predictive models without training data, and genes expressed in a single cell type that is poorly represented in available tissues will not be well interrogated with the method, which has been widely acknowledged in the original publications as a limitation of the method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“False positive rate is high but unquantifiable”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would Wainberg et al. consider traditional GWAS to have a high false positive rate due to the large number of associations attributable to LD?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TWAS is simply a weighted burden test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We agree that it is a weighted burden test analytically, but of course the weights have meaning, and that is the effect of the variants on gene expression. Therefore, this weighted burden test is exactly what it purports to be: an association test of a trait with genetically regulated expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is the results of discussions among (in alphabetic order)
Nancy Cox,
Eric Gamazon,
Laura Huckins,
Hae Kyung Im,
Douglas  Ruderfer,
Pamela Sklar, and
Eli Stahl.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome prediction models are robust across populations</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/robustnes-across-populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 17:19:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/robustnes-across-populations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most GWAS and eQTL studies have been performed in European samples. So how well do models trained in Europeans translate to other populations? Segal et al have shown that predictions of gene expression levels are robust across populations (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1003396&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following figure shows the p-value of the correlation between predicted and observed expression levels in European and African samples from the 1000 Genomes set (GEUVADIS RNA-seq) using model trained in GTEx with majority European individuals. As expected performance decreases (blue is more significant than red) when we apply to African samples but the correlation is still quite significant.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/geuvadis-performance-EUR-AFR.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---

So et al use S-PrediXcan to find psychiatric drug repositioning candidates.

## to add figure
![](https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/so2017.png)
---&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the phenome-wide consequences of genetically regulated molecular traits</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-19-ashg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-19-ashg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Apps</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/project/web-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:08:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/project/web-apps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are releasing all PrediXcan associations based on Neale Lab&#39;s UKB rapid GWAS results</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/ubk-neale-predixcan-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 15:38:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/ubk-neale-predixcan-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Update (11/1/2017)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gene level results &amp;ldquo;meta analyzed&amp;rdquo; across tissues now available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shinyapp to directly query by gene and phenotype is &lt;a href=&#34;http://UKBBeta.gene2pheno.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; but can be slow. Stay tuned for faster version coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many of you may know, Neale Lab made a big splash in the GWAS community by releasing the summary results of 2400+ phenotypes from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nealelab.is/blog/2017/7/19/rapid-gwas-of-thousands-of-phenotypes-for-337000-samples-in-the-uk-biobank&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UK Biobank&lt;/a&gt;.
Following their lead on open science and open data sharing, we are releasing the bulk runs of PrediXcan association based on Neale Lab&amp;rsquo;s UKB results and 44 tissues models from GTEx V6p release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All PrediXcan associations can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ukb-neale.gene2pheno.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also generating a &amp;ldquo;meta analyzed&amp;rdquo; across tissues version, which we find much more easily interpretable. They will be uploaded within the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this is work in progress, so feedback is greatly appreciated! We are trying to flag some suspicous results (likely false positives) but so please let us know if you find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Web app for query (Shinyapp) will be rolled out shortly, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical methods to explore the phenotypic consequences of gene regulation</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-13-wcpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 18:51:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-10-13-wcpg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Friday, October 13, 2017 from 8:00am - 3:45pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImLab was awarded NIH Cloud Credit</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/nih-cloud-credit-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 10:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/nih-cloud-credit-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to be awarded NIH Cloud Credit that will help us fund our cloud-based web applications and databases and broadly share our tools and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Jiamao, for pushing this through 👍😃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information about Cloud Credits &lt;a href=&#34;https://commonfund.nih.gov/bd2k/cloudcredits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U4C Challenge Winners</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/u4c-challenge-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 10:19:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/u4c-challenge-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two out of 4 winners used PrediXcan 👍👍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners of &amp;ldquo;Up For A Challenge (U4C): Stimulating innovation in breast cancer genetic epidemiology&amp;rdquo; papers published on line &lt;a href=&#34;http://collections.plos.org/up-for-a-challenge&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is our contribution in collaboration with Guimin Gao, Brandon Pierce, Funmi Olopade, and Dezheng Huo &lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006727&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link to paper here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the phenotypic consequences of every human gene...</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-13-rising-starts-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 08:28:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-13-rising-starts-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medicine.uchicago.edu/files/2017/08/Rising_Stars_Poster_FINAL.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Event Poster PDF here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating GWAS, omics, and electronic medical records to dissect disease biology</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-08-gcd-iges-joint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 20:05:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/talk/2017-09-08-gcd-iges-joint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S-PrediXcan (MetaXcan) in drug repositioning</title>
      <link>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/drug-repositioning-metaxcan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hakyimlab.org/post/2017/drug-repositioning-metaxcan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So et al use S-PrediXcan to find psychiatric drug repositioning candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/imlab-open/Webdata/Images/2017/so2017.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
